## Chuanxia Zheng

## Research Interests

His research interests focus on computer vision and machine learning, especially for generative models. He has done a wide range of work on 2D and 3D scene synthesis, with the goal of *synthesizing a photorealistic virtual world* via generative AI. In particular, on topics:

- $\circ~$  3D reconstruction and generation from limited views or videos.
- 3D editing (e.g., decomposition, recomposition, and completion) via object-centric perception.
- Generative models for physical world understanding.
- Multi-modalities (1D, 2D, 3D, and 4D) generation and understanding.

## Education

Nanyang Technological University	2017.08-2021.07
Ph.D. in Computer Science, SCSE	
Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning	
Advisors: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai	
Beihang University	2014.09-2017.03
MA.E. in Automation Science	
Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot	
Advisors: Jianhua Wang and Weihai Chen	
Beijing Jiaotong University	2010.09-2014.07
B.E. in Electronic and Information Engineering	
Highest Honours (Outstanding Graduate of Beijing), Advisor: Ze Liu	
Employment	
University of Oxford	2022.12-now
PostDoctoral Researcher Fellow in Computer Vision	
Research interests: 2D and 3D scene synthesis using unsupervised learning	
Tap Mobile	2022.09-2022.11
AI research counselor in computer vision and machine learning group	
Research interests: 2D image generation, completion and translation	
Monash University	2021.08-2022.08
Postdoctoral Research Fellow at Monash Research Institute of Science and Technology	2021.00
Research interests: 2D image generation and 3D generation	
Huawei Research	2017.01-2017.06
Research assistant at Noah's Ark Lab	
Research interests: face recognition and generation	
Tencent Research	2016.05-2016.09
Research Intern at Fundamental Research Center of Tencent	
Work on news recommendation	
Research Experience	
VinAI, The national AI research Lab of Vietnam, Vietnam, Dr. Hung Bui	2021.11-2022.08
Cooperator on high quality image generation and data compression	
three papers accepted by NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), ICML(1)	
Department of Data Science & AI, Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai	2021.08-2022.08
Research interests: nature scene generation and completion	
three papers accepted by CVPR(1), ECCV(2), one paper submitted to TPAMI	
Mechanobiology Institue (MBI), NUS, Singapore, Prof. Lim Chwee Teck	2020.01-2021.10
institute (institute (institute institute inst	2020.01 2021.10

Cooperator on cell nuclear generation one paper accepted by Plos one(1) Institute for Media Innovation (IMI), NTU, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann 2017.08-2021.06 Research interests: photorealistic image generation seven papers accepted by CVPR(2), ECCV(1), ICCV(1), SIGGRAPH(1) and IJCV(2)2014.09-2017.03 IR&MCT Lab, Beihang University, China, Prof. Weihai Chen Research interests: secne understanding and segmentation Awards & Honors CVPR 2023 Outstanding Reviewers (232/7000+) 2023 NeurIPS 2022 Scholar/Travel Award 2022 NTU Presidential Postdoctoral Fellowship 2022 NTU Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022 TMM Outstanding Reviewer Award 2021 NTU Research Scholarship 2017 Outstanding Graduate of Beijing 2014 National Second Prize of the National Electronic Design Contest of China (Best one in Beijing) 2013 Hanergy Scholarship Award (**Top 1**%) 2012 Siemens Scholarship Award (**Top 1**%) 2011 Press Coverage Sber.ru: MoVQ — 0.1 means a lot for text-image generation Kandinsky 2.1 (Github: 2.3K) 2023 Phys.org: Researchers unravel cell biology through artificial intelligence 2022 NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022 2022 Zhuanzhi: How to create photorealistic images? Ph.D. Thesis by Dr. Zheng 2022 kknews, Sohu, NetEase: AgileGAN — a tool for creating stylized portraits (Demo: 10K in 7 days) 2021 Academic Services Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer..... CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT 2023.06 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU 2023.04 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford 2023.04 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link 2022.09 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford 2022.08 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH 2022.06 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC 2022.01 Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU 2019.11 Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU 2018.06

Teaching

<b>Teaching</b> , Generative AI, Graduate, Oxford	2023-2023
Teaching Assistant, Advanced Digital Image Processing, Graduate, NTU	2018-2020
Teaching Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction, Undergraduate, NTU	2018-2020
Teaching Assistant, Engineering Mathematics, Undergraduate, NTU	2018–2019
Advising	
PhD students	
Zeyu Wang, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-present
Fengming Liu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-present
Tianhao Wu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-present
Minghui Hu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2022-present
Yuedong Chen, Monash University, co-supervised with Prof. Jianfei Cai	2021-present

Publications CVPR(3), ECCV(3), ICCV(2), NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), ICML(1), IJCV(2), SIGGRAPH(1)

Jingbo Zhao, University of Oxford, Undergraduate Part B extend Essay

[20] Chuanxia Zheng and Andrea Vedaldi. Online clustered codebook. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision(ICCV)*, 2023.

2023-present

- [19] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Vector quantized wasserstein auto-encoder. In *The Fortieth International Conference on Machine Learning* (*ICML*), 2023.
- [18] Minghui Hu, Chuanxia Zheng, Heliang Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Zuopeng Yang, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Ponnuthurai N. Suganthan. Unified discrete diffusion for simultaneous vision-language generation. In The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.
- [17] Chuanxia Zheng, Long Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. In *Thirty-sixth Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems* (NeurIPS), 2022.
- [16] Jyothsna Vasudevan\*, **Chuanxia Zheng**\*, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. From qualitative data to correlation using deep generative networks: Demonstrating the relation of nuclear position with the arrangement of actin filaments. *PloS one*, 17(7):e0271056, 2022.
- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, Chuanxia Zheng, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.
- [13] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition*(CVPR), pages 11512–11522, June 2022.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021.
- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision*(*ICCV*), pages 11645–11655, 2021.

- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV), 129(10):2786–2805, 2021.
- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. *ACM Transactions on Graphics* (*TOG*), 40(4):1–13, 2021.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR)*, pages 16407–16417, 2021.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, pages 1438–1447, 2019.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, Chuanxia Zheng, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In 2019 IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP), pages 1–4. IEEE, 2019.
- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pages 767–783, 2018.
- [4] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 34(5):735–747, 2018.
- [3] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 33(12):1587–1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In 2016 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO), pages 862–867. IEEE, 2016.
- [1] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In 2016 IEEE 11th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA), pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

## Preprints

- [7] Tianhao Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Ipo-ldm: Depth-aided 360-degree indoor rgb panorama outpainting via latent diffusion model. *Under reviewer on ICLR*.
- [6] Guanqi Zhan, Chuanxia Zheng, Weidi Xie, and Andrew Zisserman. Amodal completion in the wild. Under reviewer on NeurIPS.
- [5] LongTung Vuong, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Manh Luong, Thanh-Toan Do, Dinh Phung, and Trung Le. Kefi: Kernel-based feature identification for generalizable classification. *Under reviewer on NeurIPS*.
- [4] Minghui Hu, Jianbin Zheng, Daqing Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Tat-Jen Cham. Cocktail: Mixing multi-modality control for text-conditional image generation. *Under reviewer on NeurIPS*.
- [3] Yuedong Chen, Haofei Xu, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Explicit correspondence matching for generalizable neural radiance fields. *Under reviewer on 3DV*.
- [2] Yuzhu Ji, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. One-shot human motion transfer via occlusion-robust flow prediction and neural texturing. *Under reviewer on TNNLS*.
- [1] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. High-quality pluralistic image completion via code sharing. *Under reviewer on TPAMI*.